CYNTHIA GARCIA

Austin, TX 78744 ● i.cynthiagarcia@gmail.com ● (940) 320-9277

https://linked.com/in/i-cynthiagarcia • https://github.com/caersun • https://cynthiagarcia.work

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with an arts, education, and science background. Earned a certificate from the University of Texas in full-stack development. Passionate about creating web applications with a focus on increased user accessibility. Adaptable and quick problem solving to prioritize UX/UI and end goals. Collaborative, self-motivated, and curious researcher. Oral and written Spanish fluency.

SKILLS

- Languages: Terminal, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSX, SQL, NoSQL
- Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, Sequelize, Heroku
- Tools: Node, Materialize, ¡Query, AJAX, Handlebars, Express, React, Redux, APIs, Restful API

PROJECTS

Home to Home ● https://github/com/caersun/hometohome ● https://hometohome.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A MERN e-commerce site to connect entrepreneurial homecooks and their hungry neighbors.
- Role: Lead full-stack engineer
- Tools: Node, Express, Passport, Sequelize, React, Redux, Cloudinary

It's a Blog's Life! • https://github.com/Cenzo-cmd/A-Blog's-Life/ • https://its-a-blogs-life.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A blogging site to share your thoughts, find new friends, and give feedback to others' content in the form of comments and likes.
- Role: Back end and database designer

IDEA Montopolis College Preparatory, IDEA Public Schools

• Tools: Handlebars, Materialize, ¡Query, Node, Express, Passport, Sequelize

Survive 2020 • https://github.com/Mattmoe1/Survive-2020/ • https://mattmoe1.github.io/Survive-2020/

- Summary: A choose-your-own-adventure, text-based game parodying the interesting year 2020.
- Role: Front end engineer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, Bulma.io

EXPERIENCE

AP Biology Teacher

Austin, TX

• Constructed curriculum, managed classroom including grading, behavior, and tutoring, and implemented targeted. plans for individual students, driving student achievement for historically low-performing cohorts.

Writing Consultant

August 2016-May 2018

August 2018–July 2020

University of North Texas, Writing Center

Denton, TX

- Tutored clients one-on-one on their English writing, grammar, and planning skills through collaborative discussion.
- Developed plans with long-term clients for how to tackle long-form writing, projects, and theses.

Researcher, SEA-PHAGES

August 2014–May 2016

Howard Hughes Medical Institute

Denton, TX

- Collaborated to isolate bacteriophage DNA and submitted phage genome for sequencing under Dr. Lee Hughes.
- Analyzed and annotated bacteriophage genome through BLAST bioinformatics.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

January 2020

University of Texas

Austin, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Biology & Bachelor of Arts in English

May 2018

University of North Texas

Denton, TX